The ML Marketplace is moving towards increasing levels of Machine Learning abstraction.
ML市場では 機械学習の 抽象化レベルが高まっています
Aucnet built their own custom model to classify car parts and estimate the price.
オークネットは独自のカスタムモデルを構築し 車の分類や査定を行っています
But that was a custom model built from scratch.
これは一から構築したカスタムモデルです
Ocado was able to build off the natural language API.
オカドは自然言語APIを基にしたモデルで
So, they parsed results from the NL API and used it to route customer emails.
このAPIの結果を解析し 顧客メールを分類しました
They were not starting from scratch,
一から構築したわけではなく
they were starting from one level higher,
一段階進んで
restarting from a natural language API and they could use the sentiment and
自然言語APIを利用して メールから感情や内容を抽出し
entities from that API to help them their routing decisions.
担当部署の決定に役立てました
Giphy, which is the third level of abstraction on this slide,
Giphyは3番目に高度な抽象化レベルです
Giphy uses the vision API to find the text in memes,
Vision APIでミーム上の文字を検出し
and it uses optical character recognition.
光学式文字認識を使用します
So, here Giphy is able to use a vision API as is to find text in memes.
ミーム上の文字の検出に Vision APIをそのまま使えるわけです
A social media company,
ソーシャルメディア企業も
as another example uses a vision API to reject inappropriate uploads.
Vision APIで不適切な アップロードを拒否します
That's another example of using the API as is to solve a business problem.
ビジネス問題を解決するために APIをそのまま使用している例です
And the final, on the right hand side,
最後に 右側にあるのが
is a much higher level abstraction.
さらに高度な抽象化です
For example, Uniqlo used design a shopping chatbot using
ユニクロはDialogflowを使用して
Dialogflow and they were able to use
買い物用チャットボットを設計し
Dialogflow to create a completely new shopping experience.
まったく新しいショッピング体験を 作成しました
And this is something that you will see over and over
こうした事例があちこちで見られます
again where things used to be done with custom image models.
カスタム画像モデルの代わりです
Over time, we're going to go towards increasing levels of
今後 MLによる抽象化はさらに高度になり
ML abstraction following the typical journey of most software,
ソフトウェア開発の 典型的な歴史をたどるでしょう
where you tend to build things at a very low level
技術がまだ新しく未熟なうちは
while the technology is still new and maturing.
非常に低いレベルで開発を進め
And as the technology matures,
技術の向上と共に
things start to get more and more abstract and much more high level.
抽象化の量やレベルを高めていきます
In this specialization, we're going to be focusing on building custom machine models.
この専門コースでは
and the level of abstraction that we are going to work at
ここでの抽象化レベルは
will be around building custom models.
カスタムモデルの構築に沿ったものです
But be aware that increasingly,
しかし注意すべき点は
you will get to incorporate Machine Learning into
今後は 主にAPIの形で
your applications primarily in the form of APIs.
機械学習をアプリに組み込むことが 増えるということです
Of course, somebody will have to build these APIs for the marketplace and perhaps,
もちろん 誰かが機械学習APIを 構築する必要があります
you are the builder of such Machine Learning API.
それはあなたかもしれませんね